

3911 SW 160th Ave. #308

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Nine years of full-time, post-Master's degree experience in residential life with progressive responsibility. Functional experiences include administration; assessment; crisis response; marketing; programming; staff selection, training, and supervision; and student conduct. Additional experience in conflict mediation; multiculturalism; student housing assignments; and working collaboratively with community agencies and other units.

EDUCATION

Doctorate of Education in Higher Education, ABD

Florida International University, Miami, FL.

Dissertation Topic: "First-Year Residential Students' Parents' Separation Anxiety"

Master of Science in Education

Eastern Illinois University, Charleston, IL, May 1998

Bachelor of Science

Western Illinois University, Macomb, IL, July 1996

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Director of Residential Life, Florida International University

June 2002 to Present

- Assist in the direction of the residential life program for 3000 students
- Member of Senior Staff administrative leadership team, providing self-evaluation, goal setting, vision, and planning for the Department of Housing and Residential Life
- Provide leadership to Residential Life staff comprised of 8 Master's degree staff, 9 Graduate Assistants, 72 Resident Assistants, and 10 Academic Peer Assistants
- Directly supervise 4 full-time, Master's degree Residence Life Coordinators and a Summer ACUHO-I Intern
- Supervise Master's of Science in Higher Education Administration practicum students
- Oversee residential life student conduct process and serve as a hearing officer
- Oversee professional staff and student staff recruitment and selection processes
- Serve as a liaison and representative with other Student Affairs and university offices
- Design, implement, and execute assessment measures including annual surveys and focus groups
- Assist in the production of departmental literature
- Respond to residential community and student crises via on-call duty rotation
- Represent the department on various Divisional and University committees

Coordinator for Programming and Development, Florida International University June 2001 to June 2002

- Coordinated Resident Assistant recruitment and selection
- Responsible for Resident Assistant pre-service course
- Coordinated training and in-services for student staff and professional staff
- Coordinated department's student conduct system and served as a hearing officer
- Coordinated department's programming efforts
- Assisted with living and learning programs and implementation of academic initiatives
- Assisted with implementation of assessment projects

- Administer the overall operations of a co-ed residence hall complex housing approximately 437 students
- Responsible for administering student occupancy and coordinating resident room changes
- Supervise 1 Facilities Manager, 15 Resident Assistants, 3 Office Assistants; indirectly supervise 18 Desk Receptionists
- Work collaboratively with live-in hall ministers, Building Mechanic, Custodial, and Dining Management
- Coordinate programming to be congruent with University mission-based programming model
- Serve as Judicial Officer for the residence hall
- Advise Student Conduct Board and serve as Judicial Officer for the Office of Student Development
- Represent Office of Residence Life at University Preview and Orientation events
- Collaboratively managed a 20 room Guest Wing program for University guests
- Monitor a residence hall budget of approximately \$80,000
- Respond to service-related inquiries of University conference guests
- Assume and supervise on call crisis management operations associated with on-call duty rotation
- Advise the residence hall council
- · Advised the campus National Residence Hall Honorary chapter
- · Coordinate all aspects of staff training
- Supervise the coordination of First Friday; a campus-wide alcohol alternative program
- Summer 2000 assignment: Assistant to the Coordinator for Housing & Conference Services
 - o Conducted a telephone survey assessing current housing marketing instruments
 - o Assisted with the departmental student room assignment process
 - o Responded to student and parent concerns regarding building and room assignments

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Strengths Philosophy Training Facilitator, Case Western Reserve University Strengths Philosophy Training Facilitator, Starbucks Corporation First Year Student Experience Instructor, Florida International University ACUHO-I Intern, Northwest Missouri State University, Maryville, MO. Associate Hall Director, Eastern Illinois University, Charleston, IL. Senior Resident Assistant, Western Illinois University, Macomb, IL. Resident Assistant, Western Illinois University, Macomb, IL.

June, 2007 October, 2006 Fall 2002 to Fall 2004 Summers 1997 and 1998 July 1996 to May 1998 January 1996 to July 1996 August 1994 to December 1995

SELECTED PRESENTATIONS

Thompson, R., Onorato, S., and Vega, G. (2004). Exploring the impact of peer tutoring on students' academic success. Presentation at the American College Personnel Association Annual Convention, Philadelphia, PA.

Thompson, R. and Onorato, S. (2004). Inviting excellence, choosing ethics. Presentation at the American College Personnel Association Annual Convention, Philadelphia, PA.

Thompson, R.; Onorato, S.; and Vega, G. (2004). FIU's academic plan; Exploring a worthwhile experience. Presentation at the American College Personnel Association Annual Convention, Philadelphia, PA.

Thompson, R.; Vega, G.; and Camp, A. (2005) Advancing minority employees' experience: Enhancing organizational culture. Presentation at the American College Personnel Association Annual Convention, Nashville, TN.

Thompson, R. (2006). The difference we make in our students' lives: The parental perspective. Presentation at the American College Personnel Association Annual Convention, Indianapolis, IN.

Thompson, R.; Brown, D.; and Royer, R. (2005). Sportsman-like conduct: Establishing guidelines to help staff in ethical decision-making. Presented at Southeastern Association of Housing Officers Annual Conference. Hilton Head, SC.

LEADERSHIP & SERVICE

American College Personnel Association

ACPA Commission III Directorate Body Member, 1999 to 2002

- Vice Chair, March 2000 to April 2002
- Model Program Booklet Committee Chair, 1999 to 2000
- Multi-Cultural Resource Guide Committee, 1999 to 2000

Southeastern Association of Housing Officers (SEAHO)

- Research and Information Committee
 - o Member 2003-2004
 - o Chairperson 2004 to 2007

Florida International University

Emergency Management Group, 2007 to present

Student Affairs Assessment Advisory Committee, 2007 to present

Ethics Committee Chairperson, 2002 to 2003

Professional Staff Training Committee, 2002, 2003, and 2005

Safety Task Force Chairperson, Summer 2004

Safety Committee Chairperson, Summer 2005

University Safety Committee, March 2003 to present

University Consultation Team, January 2006 to present

University Substance Abuse Taskforce, March 2003 to Present

Violence Against Women Grant Task Force, 2002 to 2005

Student Affairs Staff Development Committee, 2003 to 2005

Student Affairs Graduate Assistant Visit Days Committee, 2003 to Present

Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King Annual Commemorative Breakfast Committee, 2002 to 2006

Sigma Sigma Sorority Faculty Advisor, 2002 to 2004

Student Affairs Assessment Committee, 2001 to 2003

Marquette University

University Mission Development Team, 1999 to 2000

Marquette University Programmers, MU, 2000 to 2001

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

American College Personnel Association (ACPA) Member 1996 to present

ACPA Conference 1998, 1999, 2000, 2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, 2007, and 2008 (anticipated)

CALCASA Conference, Birmingham, AL, March, 2003

Great Lakes Association of College and University Housing Officers (GLACUHO) Conference 1996

National Association of Student Personnel Administrators (NASPA) Member 1996 to present

Southeastern Association of Housing Officers (SEAHO) Conference 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, and 2006

AWARDS & RECOGNITION

TIAA-CREF Torch Award, Florida International University President's Award for Leadership in Ethics, 2005 Service to Commisssion III Award, American College Personnel Association, 2002

COMPUTER SKILLS

Proficient with current versions of the following software applications:

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Image Ready Microsoft AccessFront Page PowerPoint

Adobe In-Design Adobe Photoshop Microsoft ExcelPower Point SPSS

Adobe Page Maker File Maker Pro Microsoft Front Page